howardwilson

contact

howard@watsonbox.net

github.com/watsonbox watsonbox.github.com

languages

english mother tongue fluent french

programming

Ruby / Rails Ember.js, React, Swift CSS3 / HTML5 / ES6 Browserify & Gulp AWS/EC2, Git, RSpec

open source

pocketsphinx-ruby ios_google_places xbmc-confreaks exportify

profile

Highly motivated I.T. professional, capable of integrating quickly into existing teams, applying relevant skills and technologies where appropriate. Experienced in achieving the highest standards of development, with careful appreciation of project timescales and resource. Good communication skills; confident and articulate.

education

2001–2004 **Computer Science** BSc Hons

The University of Warwick, England

Paris, France

First Class - 80% Average.

Freelance - Various Projects

Third Year Project - 89% awarded 'Project of the Year 2004'.

experience

2014-Now

	Ember.js, React.js, Swift/iOS, RoR 4.2	
2012–2014	Fanzy Technical Team Lead / CTO	Paris, France
	Ruby on Rails 3.2, Goliath, Sinatra, AWS/EC2/RDS, Social APIs, Scrum, TDD	Elasticsearch, MongoDB,
2011-2012	eYeka	Paris, France
	Senior Developer / Technical Team Lead Ruby on Rails, Gigya Social Login/Sharing	
2010-2011	Smartdate	Paris, France
	Senior Developer - Contract Ruby on Rails 2.3, AWS/EC2, NoSQL stores, matching, Facebook Graph API, Scrum, TDD	emcached, collaborative
2009-2010	Halogen Solutions Limited	Paris, France
	Managing Director - Self Employed Ruby on Rails 2.2, MySQL, Linux systems administra	ation
2008-2009	Smart Business Communications	Paris, France
	EMEA e-Learning Project Manager - Contract PHP, MySQL, Ruby on Rails 2.1, Linux systems adm	inistration
2006-2008	RM Education PIc	Didcot, Oxfordshire, UK
	Technical Team Lead - Contract C#, ASP.NET, COM+, Transact-SQL	
2006	Sygneca Ltd Web Application Developer - Contract Scala	Cliddesden, Hampshire, UK
2004-2006	Dorset Software Services .NET/C# Consultant Analyst Programmer	Poole, Dorset, UK